## Syed Ishtiak Rahman

Dhaka, Bangladesh.

srahman191120@bscse.uiu.ac.bd • +880-1623-181997 linkedin.com/in/syed-ishtiak-rahman qithub/Ishti97

ishtiak.xyz

Enthusiastic Computer Science graduate with a passion for problem-solving, deep interest in Software Engineering and Machine Learning. Significant hands-on experience building applications from scratch through multiple projects using a wide array of technologies like MERN, Django, and PHP(native). Developed projects on prediction and forecasting, build applications using Deep Learning, and Computer Vision. Seek opportunities to enhance expertise through continuous learning and professional development.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

#### UNITED INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant and Grader

October 2022 - May 2023 Dhaka, Bangladesh

• Assisted faculties in teaching undergraduate courses.

**FIVERR PLATFORM** 

April 2020 - Nov 2021 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Freelancer

- Wrote small application with Java, Python
- Developed script and GUI application with Python/Tkinter.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

Agriculture 4.0 in Bangladesh: Issues and Challenges.

SKIMA-2022

Dec 2022 Cambodia

• This paper aims to propose a framework with Big Data and IoT based architecture for Bangladesh agriculture based on the existing research advancements.

A Comprehensive Review on Precision Agriculture and Machine Learning Approach in Bangladesh.

April 2023

12CT-2023

Pune, India

• . This paper provides an in-depth review of the research on ML applications in Bangladesh agricultural systems focusing disease detection, crop price and yield prediction.

## Green IoT Based Automated door Hydroponics Farming System

ICICNIS-2023

May 2023

Pune, India

• This paper proposes a fully automated hydroponics system along with the integration of green IoT which ensures an environmentfriendly, energy-saving, sustainable farming method.

## **EDUCATION**

### UNITED INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

2019-2023

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Thesis: Machine Learning for Big Data Mining in Agriculture 4.0: Crop Price Prediction project
- Coursework: Software Engineering, Data Science
- CGPA: 3.71
- Merit Scholarship (50-100 %), United International University, [2021-2022]

## **PROJECTS**

EaseTask MERN | JWT | Redux 2023

• Task managing web application to manage ongoing, upcoming and finished task. • User authentication system and profile manage. • JWS token generate and Http-Only cookie set. Eatery 2023 PHP | MySQL | JavaScript | Html | CSS • Restaurant management system for a cafeteria having multiple restaurants. • Check the restaurant's crowd and order available food. • Adjust the cart and order food while managing the inventory system. Simple Social 2020 Django | MySQL • Get user authentication and create educative posts on different categorical groups. • Create new groups and posts as necessary. LetsTrade 2020 JAVA | JAVAFx | Sqlite • Desktop appliation for sales and management of product, customer, and supplier. Adjust sales and products for incoming and outgoing product • Relation between product-customer, product-supplier **Crop Price Prediction** 2022 Machine Learning | Deep Learning • Forecast crops prices of Bangladesh based on government dataset and analyze how commodities prices raised/dropped by years • Supervised learning models, Ensemble models, LSTM-CNN model Foot Ulcer Segmentation 2023 Computer Vision | Deep Learning • Novel Fusion Approaches for Foot Ulcer Segmentation by developing different models using DeepLabv3 and compare them. **SKILLS Programming Languages** • C++ Python PHP Java JavaScript TypeScript **Backend Framework** Node.js Django Express Flask Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning TensorFlow Matplotlib Scikit-learn Pandas NumPq

**Database Technologies** 

- SQL
- MySQL

• MongoDB

# DevOps

• Git

• Selenium

• Jira

• Trello